<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Louis&#039; Footprint</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?feed=rss2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp</link>
	<description>So I can remember things.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 14:36:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.6.12</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Eggplant Satay with Coconut Teriyaki</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=181</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 14:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=181</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1/4 cup coconut milk 2 tablespoons peanut butter 1/2 cup Soy Vay® Island Teriyaki 1 large globe eggplant, peeled and cut into 1-inch cubes Olive oil, for brushing Salt and pepper, to taste If using wooden skewers, place them in a shallow dish with water to cover. Soak for at least 30 minutes. Preheat oven &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=181" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Eggplant Satay with Coconut Teriyaki</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1/4 cup coconut milk<br />
2 tablespoons peanut butter<br />
1/2 cup Soy Vay® Island Teriyaki<br />
1 large globe eggplant, peeled and cut into 1-inch cubes<br />
Olive oil, for brushing<br />
Salt and pepper, to taste</p>
<p>If using wooden skewers, place them in a shallow dish with water to cover. Soak for at least 30 minutes. Preheat oven to broil. Line a baking sheet with aluminum foil, and coat with nonstick cooking spray.<br />
In a small bowl, whisk together the coconut milk, peanut butter and teriyaki sauce. Set aside.<br />
Thread four pieces of eggplant on each skewer. Spread out on baking sheet and brush all four sides of each skewer with olive oil. Sprinkle with a little bit of salt and pepper.<br />
Brush the tops of the eggplant skewers with the sauce, and place under the broiler. Broil for 4-5 minutes total, flipping a quarter turn after each minute to brush exposed sides with more sauce.<br />
The skewers are ready when all four sides have been directly under the broiler, brushed with sauce, and the tops are bubbling and golden.<br />
Remove from oven, cool slightly, and serve with extra sauce for dipping.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tuna Fish Salad with White Beans</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=177</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 21:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=177</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ingredients 2 6oz cans albacore tuna, packed in olive oil 2 15 o cans cannellini white beans, drained and rinsed 1/3 cup small capers, drained and rinsed 6 tbl red wine vinegar 1 medium red onion, sliced thin 1.5 c cherry tomatoes 2 cups fresh arugula 6 fresh basil leaves sea salt black peper Add &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=177" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Tuna Fish Salad with White Beans</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients<br />
2 6oz cans albacore tuna, packed in olive oil<br />
2 15 o cans cannellini white beans, drained and rinsed<br />
1/3 cup small capers, drained and rinsed<br />
6 tbl red wine vinegar<br />
1 medium red onion, sliced thin<br />
1.5 c cherry tomatoes<br />
2 cups fresh arugula<br />
6 fresh basil leaves<br />
sea salt<br />
black peper</p>
<p>Add tuna to large bowl and reserve olive oil. Break tuna into small pieces and add beans and capers. Mix 1 part red wine vinegar to 2 parts olive oil and season w/ salt and pepper. Pour dressing onto tuna mixture and allow to infuse. Add onion and tomatoes and toss gently. Serve over fresh argula and tear basil over the top.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lentil Salad</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=176</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 23:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=176</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lentil Salad with Olives, Mint, and Feta Serves 4 to 6 French green lentils, or lentilles du Puy, are our preferred choice for this recipe, but it works with any type of lentil except red or yellow. Brining helps keep the lentils intact, but if you don’t have time, they’ll still taste good. The salad &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=176" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Lentil Salad</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lentil Salad with Olives, Mint, and Feta Serves 4 to 6<br />
French green lentils, or lentilles du Puy, are our preferred choice for this recipe, but it works with any type of lentil except red or yellow. Brining helps keep the lentils intact, but if you don’t have time, they’ll still taste good. The salad can be served warm or at room temperature.<br />
1 cup lentils, picked over and rinsed S<br />
alt and pepper<br />
2 cups low-sodium chicken broth<br />
5 garlic cloves, lightly crushed and peeled<br />
1 bay leaf<br />
5 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil<br />
3 tablespoons white wine vinegar<br />
1 / 2 cup coarsely chopped pitted kalamata olives<br />
1 / 2 cup fresh mint leaves, chopped<br />
1 large shallot, minced<br />
1 ounce feta cheese, crumbled (1/4 cup) </p>
<p>1. Place lentils and 1 teaspoon salt in bowl. Cover with 4 cups warm water (about 110 degrees) and soak for 1 hour. Drain well. (Drained lentils can be refrigerated for up to 2 days before cooking.) 2. Adjust oven rack to middle position and heat oven to 325 degrees. Place drained lentils, 2 cups water, broth, garlic, bay leaf, and ½ teaspoon salt in medium saucepan. Cover and bake until lentils are tender but remain intact, 40 to 60 minutes. Meanwhile, whisk oil and vinegar together in large bowl. 3. Drain lentils well; remove garlic and bay leaf. Add drained lentils, olives, mint, and shallot to dressing and toss to combine. Season with salt and pepper to taste. Transfer to serving dish, sprinkle with feta, and serve</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pumpkin Ginger Cupcakes</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=175</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 23:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=175</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[INGREDIENTS: 2 cups all-purpose flour 1 (3.4 ounce) package instant butterscotch pudding mix 2 teaspoons baking soda 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 tablespoon ground cinnamon 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger 1/2 teaspoon ground allspice 1/4 teaspoon ground cloves 1/3 cup finely chopped crystallized ginger 1 cup butter, room temperature 1 cup white sugar 1 cup packed brown &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=175" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Pumpkin Ginger Cupcakes</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>INGREDIENTS:<br />
2 cups all-purpose flour<br />
1 (3.4 ounce) package instant<br />
butterscotch pudding mix<br />
2 teaspoons baking soda<br />
1/4 teaspoon salt<br />
1 tablespoon ground cinnamon<br />
1/2 teaspoon ground ginger<br />
1/2 teaspoon ground allspice<br />
1/4 teaspoon ground cloves<br />
1/3 cup finely chopped crystallized ginger<br />
1 cup butter, room temperature<br />
1 cup white sugar<br />
1 cup packed brown sugar<br />
4 eggs<br />
1 teaspoon vanilla extract<br />
1 (15 ounce) can pumpkin puree</p>
<p>DIRECTIONS:<br />
1.	Preheat an oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Grease 24 muffin cups, or line with paper muffin liners. Whisk together the flour, pudding mix, baking soda, salt, cinnamon, ground ginger, allspice, cloves, and crystallized ginger in a bowl; set aside.<br />
2.	Beat the butter, white sugar, and brown sugar with an electric mixer in a large bowl until light and fluffy. The mixture should be noticeably lighter in color. Add the room-temperature eggs one at a time, allowing each egg to blend into the butter mixture before adding the next. Beat in the vanilla and pumpkin puree with the last egg. Stir in the flour mixture, mixing until just incorporated. Pour the batter into the prepared muffin cups.<br />
3.	Bake in the preheated oven until golden and the tops spring back when lightly pressed, about 20 minutes. Cool in the pans for 10 minutes before removing to cool completely on a wire rack.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greek Feta and Cucumber Salad</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=172</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 18:24:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=172</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Stolen from http://www.cookingchanneltv.com/recipes/michael-symon/greek-feta-and-cucumber-salad.html 2 English cucumbers (also known as seedless or hothouse) Salt 1 cup crumbled feta cheese 2 tablespoons fresh oregano leaves 1 clove garlic, minced 1 shallot, minced Zest and juice of 2 lemons 2 ounces extra-virgin olive oil Slice cucumbers as thinly as you can. A mandolin or vegetable slicer will make &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=172" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Greek Feta and Cucumber Salad</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stolen from http://www.cookingchanneltv.com/recipes/michael-symon/greek-feta-and-cucumber-salad.html</p>
<p>2 English cucumbers (also known as seedless or hothouse)<br />
Salt<br />
1 cup crumbled feta cheese<br />
2 tablespoons fresh oregano leaves<br />
1 clove garlic, minced<br />
1 shallot, minced<br />
Zest and juice of 2 lemons<br />
2 ounces extra-virgin olive oil</p>
<p>Slice cucumbers as thinly as you can. A mandolin or vegetable slicer will make quick work of it. Toss together the cucumbers and a large pinch of salt in a mesh strainer set over a bowl. Combine the feta, oregano, garlic and shallots in a separate bowl. Add the lemon juice and zest and whisk in the olive oil. </p>
<p>Drain off and discard any water that has released from the cucumbers. Toss together the cucumbers and the dressing. Serve. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lowfat Chocolate Cupcakes</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=158</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 15:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Not low calorie Cupcakes: 1 1/2 cups all purpose flour 3/4 cups sugar 1/4 cup cocoa powder 2 teaspoons baking powder 1 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 teaspoon salt 2/3 cup vanilla yogurt 2/3 cup skim milk 1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract 1 cup chocolate chips Set oven to 350. Combine dry ingredients (except chocolate chips), then &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=158" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Lowfat Chocolate Cupcakes</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Not low calorie</p>
<p><strong>Cupcakes:</strong><br />
1 1/2 cups all purpose flour<br />
3/4 cups sugar<br />
1/4 cup cocoa powder<br />
2 teaspoons baking powder<br />
1 teaspoon baking soda<br />
1/2 teaspoon salt<br />
2/3 cup vanilla yogurt<br />
2/3 cup skim milk<br />
1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract<br />
1 cup chocolate chips</p>
<p>Set oven to 350.<br />
Combine dry ingredients (except chocolate chips), then mix in wet. Fold in chocolate chips.<br />
Bake 15-20 minutes (closer to 15 for me).</p>
<p><strong>Frosting:</strong><br />
1 1/3 cups confectioner&#8217;s sugar<br />
1/3 cup cocoa powder<br />
1/4 cup fat-free sour cream<br />
1/4 cup skim milk<br />
1/2 teaspoon vanilla</p>
<p>Mix until combined. NOTE: This came out waaaaay to runny, I ended up adding 3x the amount of sugar etc. Probably should halve the sour cream and milk. I also used low far sour cream.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zucchini Quinoa Burgers</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=155</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2012 17:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=155</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I came across this here: http://www.traderjoes.com/recipes/recipe.asp?rid=156 I am gonna hit TJ&#8217;s tonight and see how it goes. I may alter recipe since I want to try to grill them instead of using a skillet. 2 cups TJ&#8217;s Tri-color Quinoa, Cooked 1/2 cup TJ&#8217;s Shredded Mozzarella 1 cup TJ&#8217;s Low Fat Cottage Cheese 1 cup TJ&#8217;s &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=155" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Zucchini Quinoa Burgers</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came across this here: http://www.traderjoes.com/recipes/recipe.asp?rid=156<br />
I am gonna hit TJ&#8217;s tonight and see how it goes. I may alter recipe since I want to try to grill them instead of using a skillet.</p>
<p>2 cups TJ&#8217;s Tri-color Quinoa, Cooked<br />
1/2 cup TJ&#8217;s Shredded Mozzarella<br />
1 cup TJ&#8217;s Low Fat Cottage Cheese<br />
1 cup TJ&#8217;s Zucchini, Grated or Chopped<br />
3 TJ&#8217;s Eggs, Beaten<br />
3 Tbsp TJ&#8217;s White Whole Wheat Flour<br />
2 TJ&#8217;s Green Onion Stalks, Chopped<br />
1 cup TJ&#8217;s Panko Bread Crumbs<br />
3 Tbsp TJ&#8217;s Olive Oil<br />
1 tsp TJ&#8217;s Cumin<br />
2 Cloves TJ&#8217;s Garlic, Chopped<br />
TJ&#8217;s Salt &#038; TJ&#8217;s Pepper</p>
<p>In a large bowl, combine all ingredients except olive oil. Mixture will be sticky. If necessary add more Panko Crumbs at this point. Form into 10 patties. Refrigerate for 10 minutes or more. Add olive oil to skillet and bring to medium high heat. Add patties and cook 4 minutes on each side or until golden brown. Recipe Credit: Trader Joe&#8217;s 2012 Quintessential Quinoa Recipe Contest Winner &#8211; Deborah Stone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Intel setting VGA output on laptop right of screen</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=152</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 01:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=152</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[xrandr &#8211;output LVDS1 &#8211;auto &#8211;output VGA1 &#8211;auto &#8211;right-of LVDS1 from http://crunchbanglinux.org/forums/topic/10564/dual-monitors-extended-desktop-on-intel-card/]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>xrandr &#8211;output LVDS1 &#8211;auto &#8211;output VGA1 &#8211;auto &#8211;right-of LVDS1</p>
<p>from http://crunchbanglinux.org/forums/topic/10564/dual-monitors-extended-desktop-on-intel-card/</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Foolproof Pie Dough</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=121</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2007/11/cooks-illustrated-foolproof-pie-dough-recipe.html 2 1/2 cups (12 1/2 ounces) unbleached all-purpose flour 1 teaspoon table salt 2 tablespoons sugar 12 tablespoons (1 1/2 sticks) cold unsalted butter, cut into 1/4-inch slices 1/2 cup cold vegetable shortening, cut into 4 pieces 1/4 cup cold vodka 1/4 cup cold water Process 1 1/2 cups flour, salt, and sugar &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=121" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Foolproof Pie Dough</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2007/11/cooks-illustrated-foolproof-pie-dough-recipe.html</p>
<p>2 1/2 cups (12 1/2 ounces) unbleached all-purpose flour<br />
1 teaspoon table salt<br />
2 tablespoons sugar<br />
12 tablespoons (1 1/2 sticks) cold unsalted butter, cut into 1/4-inch slices<br />
1/2 cup cold vegetable shortening, cut into 4 pieces<br />
1/4 cup cold vodka<br />
1/4 cup cold water</p>
<p>Process 1 1/2 cups flour, salt, and sugar in food processor until combined, about 2 one-second pulses. Add butter and shortening and process until homogeneous dough just starts to collect in uneven clumps, about 15 seconds (dough will resemble cottage cheese curds and there should be no uncoated flour). Scrape bowl with rubber spatula and redistribute dough evenly around processor blade. Add remaining cup flour and pulse until mixture is evenly distributed around bowl and mass of dough has been broken up, 4 to 6 quick pulses. Empty mixture into medium bowl.</p>
<p>Sprinkle vodka and water over mixture. With rubber spatula, use folding motion to mix, pressing down on dough until dough is slightly tacky and sticks together. Divide dough into two even balls and flatten each into 4-inch disk. Wrap each in plastic wrap and refrigerate at least 45 minutes or up to 2 days.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pomegranate Molasses</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=147</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 15:36:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=147</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ingredients 4 cups pomegranate juice 1/2 cup sugar 1 tablespoon freshly squeezed lemon juice Directions For Molasses: Place the pomegranate juice, sugar and lemon juice in a 4-quart saucepan set over medium heat. Cook, stirring occasionally, until the sugar has completely dissolved. Once the sugar has dissolved, reduce the heat to medium-low and cook until &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=147" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Pomegranate Molasses</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients<br />
4 cups pomegranate juice<br />
1/2 cup sugar<br />
1 tablespoon freshly squeezed lemon juice</p>
<p>Directions</p>
<p>For Molasses: Place the pomegranate juice, sugar and lemon juice in a 4-quart saucepan set over medium heat. Cook, stirring occasionally, until the sugar has completely dissolved. Once the sugar has dissolved, reduce the heat to medium-low and cook until the mixture has reduced to 1 cup, approximately 70 minutes. It should be the consistency of thick syrup. Remove from the heat and allow to cool in the saucepan for 30 minutes. Transfer to a glass jar and allow to cool completely before covering and storing in the refrigerator for up to 6 months.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warm Bananas with Brown Sugar and Bay Leaf</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=145</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 15:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=145</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Stolen from food network 4 tablespoons unsalted butter 2 bay leaves 2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice 1 cup fresh orange juice 1 cup packed light brown sugar 2 tablespoons brandy Pinch salt 6 ripe bananas, peeled and cut on the bias into 1/3-inch slices (about 1 quart) 1/4 to 1/2 teaspoon fresh coarsely ground black &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=145" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Warm Bananas with Brown Sugar and Bay Leaf</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stolen from <a href="http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/michael-chiarello/warm-bananas-with-brown-sugar-and-bay-leaf-recipe/index.html">food network</a></p>
<p>4 tablespoons unsalted butter<br />
2 bay leaves<br />
2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice<br />
1 cup fresh orange juice<br />
1 cup packed light brown sugar<br />
2 tablespoons brandy<br />
Pinch salt<br />
6 ripe bananas, peeled and cut on the bias into 1/3-inch slices (about 1 quart)<br />
1/4 to 1/2 teaspoon fresh coarsely ground black pepper<br />
Store bought chocolate cake or ice cream, for serving<br />
Directions<br />
In large skillet over high heat, melt the butter and cook until it browns, about 3 minutes. Add the bay leaves and stand back (it may pop). Add the lemon juice, orange juice, brown sugar, brandy, and a pinch of salt. Bring the mixture up to a boil. Stir and cook until the liquid has reduced by half and it has reached a syrupy consistency, about 5 minutes. Remove the pan from the heat. Add the bananas and pepper. Stir to coat the bananas evenly. Serve immediately spooned over cake or ice cream.</p>
<p>Cooking Notes: You can make the sauce hours ahead of time. Just add the fruit after you bring the sauce back to a simmer. The fruit should be a little cool inside. Serve it with a good, store bought chocolate cake or spoon it over your favorite ice cream.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roasted Brussels Sprouts with Pomegranates and Vanilla-Pecan Butter</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=143</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 15:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Stolen from food netowork Ingredients 6 tablespoons unsalted butter, slightly softened 1 vanilla bean, seeds scraped 1/4 cup toasted pecans, chopped Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1 pound Brussels sprouts, trimmed 3 tablespoons canola oil 3 tablespoons pomegranate molasses Seeds from 1 pomegranate 1 lime, finely zested 1 tablespoon finely grated orange zest Directions &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=143" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Roasted Brussels Sprouts with Pomegranates and Vanilla-Pecan Butter</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stolen from <a href="http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/bobby-flay/roasted-brussels-sprouts-with-pomegranates-and-vanilla-pecan-butter-recipe/index.html">food netowork</a></p>
<p>Ingredients<br />
6 tablespoons unsalted butter, slightly softened<br />
1 vanilla bean, seeds scraped<br />
1/4 cup toasted pecans, chopped<br />
Salt and freshly ground black pepper<br />
1 pound Brussels sprouts, trimmed<br />
3 tablespoons canola oil<br />
3 tablespoons pomegranate molasses<br />
Seeds from 1 pomegranate<br />
1 lime, finely zested<br />
1 tablespoon finely grated orange zest<br />
Directions<br />
Combine the butter and vanilla bean seeds in a small bowl. Fold in the pecans and season with salt and pepper. Cover and refrigerate for at least 30 minutes before serving.</p>
<p>Preheat the oven to 375 degrees F.</p>
<p>Place the Brussels sprouts in a medium roasting pan and toss with the oil and season with salt and pepper. Roast in the oven until lightly golden brown, 20 minutes.</p>
<p>Remove the pan from the oven, add the pomegranate molasses and stir to combine. Return to the oven and cook until just tender, about 10 minutes longer.</p>
<p>Transfer the sprouts to a large bowl, add the pomegranate seeds and lime and orange zests. Transfer to a platter and top with some of the Vanilla-Pecan butter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mushroom Risotto</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=141</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 15:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Stolen from allrecipes Ingredients 6 cups chicken broth, divided 3 tablespoons olive oil, divided 1 pound portobello mushrooms, thinly sliced 1 pound white mushrooms, thinly sliced 2 shallots, diced 1 1/2 cups Arborio rice 1/2 cup dry white wine sea salt to taste freshly ground black pepper to taste 3 tablespoons finely chopped chives 4 &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=141" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Mushroom Risotto</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Stolen from <a href="http://allrecipes.com/recipe/gourmet-mushroom-risotto/">allrecipes</a></p>
<p>Ingredients</p>
<p>6 cups chicken broth, divided<br />
3 tablespoons olive oil, divided<br />
1 pound portobello mushrooms, thinly sliced<br />
1 pound white mushrooms, thinly sliced<br />
2 shallots, diced<br />
1 1/2 cups Arborio rice<br />
1/2 cup dry white wine<br />
sea salt to taste<br />
freshly ground black pepper to taste<br />
3 tablespoons finely chopped chives<br />
4 tablespoons butter<br />
1/3 cup freshly grated Parmesan cheese<br />
Directions</p>
<p>In a saucepan, warm the broth over low heat.<br />
Warm 2 tablespoons olive oil in a large saucepan over medium-high heat. Stir in the mushrooms, and cook until soft, about 3 minutes. Remove mushrooms and their liquid, and set aside.<br />
Add 1 tablespoon olive oil to skillet, and stir in the shallots. Cook 1 minute. Add rice, stirring to coat with oil, about 2 minutes. When the rice has taken on a pale, golden color, pour in wine, stirring constantly until the wine is fully absorbed. Add 1/2 cup broth to the rice, and stir until the broth is absorbed. Continue adding broth 1/2 cup at a time, stirring continuously, until the liquid is absorbed and the rice is al dente, about 15 to 20 minutes.<br />
Remove from heat, and stir in mushrooms with their liquid, butter, chives, and parmesan. Season with salt and pepper to taste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Streaming Live TV to Android through http</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=122</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 03:18:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=122</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I use a dvb device to record HDTV on my linux box, and want to stream the video to my new droid bionic. I found a decent solution using vlc. I mostly use this for football when I&#8217;m out of town. &#160; vlc command Took me a while to work this out: cvlc -vvv dvb:// &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=122" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Streaming Live TV to Android through http</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I use a dvb device to record HDTV on my linux box, and want to stream the video to my new droid bionic.  I found a decent solution using vlc. I mostly use this for football when I&#8217;m out of town.</p>
<p>  &nbsp;</p>
<h4>vlc command</h4>
<p>Took me a while to work this out:<br />
<code>cvlc -vvv dvb:// --dvb-frequency=<font color="red">FREQ</font> --dvb-modulation=256 --sout '#transcode{soverlay,ab=42,samplerate=44100,channels=1,acodec=mp4a,vcodec=h264,width=640,height=352,vfilter="canvas{width=640,height=352,aspect=16:9}",fps=29.97,vb=400,venc=x264{vbv-bufsize=500,partitions=all,level=12,no-cabac,subme=7,threads=4,ref=2,mixed-refs=1,bframes=0,min-keyint=1,keyint=50,trellis=2,direct=auto,qcomp=0.0,qpmax=51}}: standard{access=http,mux=ts,dst=<font color="red">IP</font>:<font color="red">PORT</font>}'<br />
</code></p>
<p>where:<br />
<font color="red">FREQ</font> is the channel frequency (2nd column in your dvbscan file)<br />
<font color="red">IP</font> is the IP address to bind to<br />
<font color="red">PORT</font> is the port (I use 8080)</p>
<p>You can see if its running properly with:<br />
<code><br />
vlc http://<font color="red">IP</font>:<font color="red">PORT</font><br />
</code><br />
on another machine.</p>
<p>  &nbsp;</p>
<h4>Playing on android</h4>
<p>I evaluated two apps to play http streams: <i>Daroon Player</i> and <i>MoboPlayer</i>. I couldn&#8217;t get <i>MoboPlayer</i> to work for more than a split second.  </p>
<p>I use <i>Daroon Player</i>. It is free and in the Market. when you open it, hit the <b>streams->menu->add</b>. Give it a name and enter<br />
<code><br />
http://<font color="red">IP</font>:<font color="red">PORT</font><br />
</code></p>
<p>You can tell daroon player to use the hardware decoding on your phone to save batter/CPU.<br />
Go to <b>menu->settings->Decoding Mode</b> and change <b>http</b> to <b>Hardware Decoding</b>.<br />
The above encoding works on the hardware decoder on my droid bionic. I&#8217;ve heard it has a TI decoding chip (vs other ones on, say, the iphone) so you may need to change things.</p>
<p>There are still some issues I have to work out:</p>
<ul>
<li> I couldn&#8217;t get audio to work using the software decoder in the Daroon Player. I really didn&#8217;t mind since I prefer the hardware decoder, but may be an issue for other phones.
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4>Script</h4>
<p>I use the following script to parse my channels file from DVB scan, and startup the server.</p>
<p><code><br />
#!/bin/bash</p>
<p>SCANFILE=~/.mplayer/channels.conf<br />
WIDTH=640<br />
HEIGHT=352<br />
ASPECT=16:9<br />
VB=400</p>
<p>if [ $1 ] ; then<br />
        FREQ=`grep ^$1: $SCANFILE | awk 'BEGIN { FS = ":" } ; { print $2 }'`;<br />
        if [ $FREQ ] ; then<br />
OP="#transcode{soverlay,ab=42,samplerate=44100,channels=1,acodec=mp4a,vcodec=h264,width=$WIDTH,height=$HEIGHT,vfilter=\"canvas{width=$WIDTH,height=$HEIGHT,aspect=$ASPECT}\",fps=29.97,vb=$VB,venc=x264{vbv-bufsize=500,partitions=all,level=12,no-cabac,subme=7,threads=4,ref=2,mixed-refs=1,bframes=0,min-keyint=1,keyint=50,trellis=2,direct=auto,qcomp=0.0,qpmax=51}}:standard{access=http,mux=ts,dst=192.168.1.102:8080}"<br />
                CMD="cvlc -vvv  dvb://  --dvb-frequency=$FREQ --dvb-modulation=256 --sout "$OP<br />
                echo $CMD<br />
                $CMD >& /dev/null<br />
        else<br />
                echo "COULD NOT FIND CHANNEL $1!!!!"<br />
                exit 1<br />
        fi<br />
else<br />
        echo "Usage: $0 [channel]"<br />
fi<br />
</code></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mom&#8217;s Cookies</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=120</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 15:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1 cup margarine 3/4 cup sugar 1 egg 1 tsp vanilla 1/8 tsp salt 1/2 tsp baking powder 2 1/2 cups flour Sift flour, salt, and baking powder, set aside. Cream butter and sugar, add egg and vanilla. Add flour mixture and mix well (by hand). Chill in fridge overnight. Roll out, cut, and bake &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=120" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Mom&#8217;s Cookies</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1 cup margarine<br />
3/4 cup sugar<br />
1 egg<br />
1 tsp vanilla<br />
1/8 tsp salt<br />
1/2 tsp baking powder<br />
2 1/2 cups flour</p>
<p>Sift flour, salt, and baking powder, set aside.  Cream butter and sugar, add<br />
egg and vanilla.  Add flour mixture and mix well (by hand).  Chill in fridge<br />
overnight.  Roll out, cut, and bake at 400º 6-8 minutes.</p>
<p>Frosting:<br />
1 lb powdered sugar<br />
1 stick margarine<br />
1 tsp vanilla<br />
Dash salt<br />
3 tbls milk (more or less, to desired texture)<br />
Beat til smooth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Salad</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=116</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=116</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a salad I make around the holidays. I don&#8217;t recall which greens I buy, typically just get what looks good. I like to mix in some bitter greens cause it goes well with the dressing and candied walnuts. I don&#8217;t know the proportions, but its a salad, so figure it out. Ingredients: Candied &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=116" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Christmas Salad</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a salad I make around the holidays. I don&#8217;t recall which greens I buy, typically just get what looks good. I like to mix in some bitter greens cause it goes well with the dressing and candied walnuts.  I don&#8217;t know the proportions, but its a salad, so figure it out.</p>
<p>Ingredients:<br />
<a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=83">Candied Walnuts</a><br />
<a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=81">Poppy Seed Dressing</a><br />
Dried Cranberries<br />
Crumbled Gorgonzola Cheese<br />
Mixed greens (I like a mix between red leaf lettuce, green leaf lettuce, arugula, a few bitter greens, whatever&#8230;)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orange Vanilla Cupcakes</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=108</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 14:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=108</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tastes like orange cream popsicles. Stolen from 52 cupcakes. 1 box Duncan Hines Orange Supreme Cake Mix 1 box Jello Vanilla Pudding (not instant) Follow directions on box and add in the box of vanilla pudding Follow rest of box instructions. I use the marshmallow frosting she mentioned as filling: 1/2 c. Marshmallow Fluff 1 &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=108" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Orange Vanilla Cupcakes</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tastes like orange cream popsicles.<br />
Stolen from 52 cupcakes.</p>
<p>1 box Duncan Hines Orange Supreme Cake Mix<br />
1 box Jello Vanilla Pudding (not instant)</p>
<p>Follow directions on box and add in the box of vanilla pudding<br />
Follow rest of box instructions.</p>
<p>I use the marshmallow frosting she mentioned as filling:<br />
1/2 c. Marshmallow Fluff<br />
1 egg whites, at room temperature<br />
1/2 c. sugar<br />
1/8 tsp. cream of tartar<br />
dash salt<br />
1/8 c. water<br />
1/2 tsp. vanilla extract</p>
<p>Combine all ingredients but vanilla in a double boiler over hot (~200 degrees) water. Beat with a hand mixer till soft peaks form. remove from heat, continue beating until stiff. Beat in vanilla.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Almond Vinaigrette</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=105</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 21:16:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=105</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From America&#8217;s Test Kitchen Good on salmon Makes about 1/2 cup Ingredients 1/3 cup almonds , toasted 2 teaspoons honey 1 teaspoon Dijon mustard 4 teaspoons white wine vinegar 1 medium shallot , minced (about 2 tablespoons) 1/3 cup extra virgin olive oil 1 tablespoon cold water 1 tablespoon chopped fresh tarragon leaves Table salt &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=105" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Almond Vinaigrette</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From America&#8217;s Test Kitchen<br />
Good on salmon</p>
<p>Makes about 1/2 cup</p>
<p>Ingredients<br />
1/3 cup almonds , toasted<br />
2 teaspoons honey<br />
1 teaspoon Dijon mustard<br />
4 teaspoons white wine vinegar<br />
1 medium shallot , minced (about 2 tablespoons)<br />
1/3 cup extra virgin olive oil<br />
1 tablespoon cold water<br />
1 tablespoon chopped fresh tarragon leaves<br />
Table salt and ground black pepper</p>
<p>Instructions<br />
Place almonds in zipper-lock bag and, using rolling pin, pound until no pieces larger than 1/2 inch remain. Combine pounded almonds, honey, mustard, vinegar, and shallot in medium bowl. Whisking constantly, drizzle in olive oil until emulsion forms. Add water and tarragon and whisk to combine, then season with salt and pepper. Serve.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Frosting</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=93</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=93</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ingredients: 1/3 cup butter 1/4 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1 pound (3 1/2 cups) sifted confectioners sugar 3 to 4 tablespoons milk Directions: Mix.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ingredients:<br />
1/3 cup butter<br />
1/4 teaspoon salt<br />
1 teaspoon vanilla extract<br />
1 pound (3 1/2 cups) sifted confectioners sugar<br />
3 to 4 tablespoons milk</p>
<p>Directions:<br />
Mix.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rueben Spread</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=90</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=90</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t remember where I got this&#8230;. 1 jar (16oz) sauerkraut, rinsed and drained 1 pkg. (8oz) cream cheese, cubed 2 cups (8oz) shredded Swiss cheese 1 pkg. (3oz) deli corned beef (chopped) 3 Tbs. prepared Thousand Island sald dressing Snack rye bread, loaf french bread, hard crackers, etc. In a 1 and 1/2 quart &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=90" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Rueben Spread</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t remember where I got this&#8230;.</p>
<p>1 jar (16oz) sauerkraut, rinsed and drained<br />
1 pkg. (8oz) cream cheese, cubed<br />
2 cups (8oz) shredded Swiss cheese<br />
1 pkg. (3oz) deli corned beef (chopped)<br />
3 Tbs. prepared Thousand Island sald dressing<br />
Snack rye bread, loaf french bread, hard crackers, etc.</p>
<p>In a 1 and 1/2 quart slow cooker, combine the first five ingredients. Cover and cook for 2 hours or until cheese has melted; stir occasionally to blend. Yields 3 and 1/2 cups.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buffalo Chicken Hot Wing Dip</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=87</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dip]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=87</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two 9.75-oz. (or 10-oz.) cans 98% fat-free chunk white chicken breast in water, drained One 8-oz. tub fat-free cream cheese, softened 1/2 cup Frank&#8217;s RedHot Original Cayenne Pepper Sauce 1/2 cup shredded part-skim mozzarella cheese 1/4 cup fat-free ranch dressing 1/4 cup fat-free Greek yogurt Directions: Preheat oven to 350 degrees. Place cream cheese in &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=87" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Buffalo Chicken Hot Wing Dip</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two 9.75-oz. (or 10-oz.) cans 98% fat-free chunk white chicken breast in water, drained<br />
One 8-oz. tub fat-free cream cheese, softened<br />
1/2 cup Frank&#8217;s RedHot Original Cayenne Pepper Sauce<br />
1/2 cup shredded part-skim mozzarella cheese<br />
1/4 cup fat-free ranch dressing<br />
1/4 cup fat-free Greek yogurt </p>
<p>Directions:<br />
Preheat oven to 350 degrees.</p>
<p>Place cream cheese in a medium bowl and stir until smooth. Mix in Frank&#8217;s RedHot, mozzarella cheese, ranch dressing, and yogurt. Stir in chicken until thoroughly combined. Spoon mixture evenly into a deep 8-inch by 8-inch baking dish.</p>
<p>Bake in the oven for 20 minutes, or until mixture is heated through.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicken Pot Pie</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=85</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=85</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think I yanked this from www.allrecipes.com 1 pound skinless, boneless chicken breast- cut into small pieces 1 cup sliced carrots 1 cup frozen green peas 1/2 cup sliced celery 1/3 cup butter 1/3 cup chopped onion 1/3 cup all-purpose flour 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 1/4 teaspoon celery seed 1 3/4 cups &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=85" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Chicken Pot Pie</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think I yanked this from www.allrecipes.com</p>
<p>1 pound skinless, boneless chicken breast- cut into small pieces<br />
1 cup sliced carrots<br />
1 cup frozen green peas<br />
1/2 cup sliced celery<br />
1/3 cup butter<br />
1/3 cup chopped onion<br />
1/3 cup all-purpose flour<br />
1/2 teaspoon salt<br />
1/4 teaspoon black pepper<br />
1/4 teaspoon celery seed<br />
1 3/4 cups chicken broth<br />
2/3 cup milk<br />
2 (9 inch) unbaked pie crusts</p>
<p>1.) Preheat oven to 425 degrees F (220 degrees C.)<br />
2.) In a saucepan, combine chicken, carrots, peas, and celery. Add water to cover and boil for 15 minutes. Remove from heat, drain and set aside.<br />
3.) In the saucepan over medium heat, cook onions in butter until soft and translucent. Stir in flour, salt, pepper, and celery seed. Slowly stir in chicken broth and milk. Simmer over medium-low heat until thick. Remove from heat and set aside.<br />
4.) Place the chicken mixture in bottom pie crust. Pour hot liquid mixture over. Cover with top crust, seal edges, and cut away excess dough. Make several small slits in the top to allow steam to escape.<br />
5.) Bake in the preheated oven for 30 to 35 minutes, or until pastry is golden brown and filling is bubbly. Cool for 10 minutes before serving.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Candied Walnuts</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=83</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=83</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Got this from http://www.101cookbooks.com They are great in salads and go well with Poppy Seed Dressing. Canola oil for frying Finely ground sea salt Ground Black pepper 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 4 cups walnut halves 1 cup confectioners&#8217; sugar, sifted Pour the oil to a depth of at least 3 inches &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=83" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Candied Walnuts</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Got this from http://www.101cookbooks.com<br />
They are great in salads and go well with <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=81">Poppy Seed Dressing</a>.</p>
<p>Canola oil for frying<br />
Finely ground sea salt<br />
Ground Black pepper<br />
1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon<br />
1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper<br />
4 cups walnut halves<br />
1 cup confectioners&#8217; sugar, sifted</p>
<p>Pour the oil to a depth of at least 3 inches into a deep fryer or a heavy, 8-inch-deep stockpot and heat to 350F. While the oil is heating, bring a large saucepan filled with water to a boil over high heat. In a small bowl, combine 1 teaspoon salt, 1/2 teaspoon pepper, the cinnamon, and the cayenne and mix well.</p>
<p>When the water is boiling, place the nuts in a sieve and dip them into the boiling water, about 1 minute for large halves, less time for smaller halves. Transfer the nuts to a large bowl with a little water clinging to them. (Blanching removes some of the tannins, making the walnuts sweeter.) While the nuts are still hot, add the sugar and toss well to coat evenly. The sugar will melt on contact with the hot nuts. Keep stirring and tossing until all the sugar has melted. If bits of unmelted sugar remain on the nuts, the nuts will not fry properly.</p>
<p>Stir the nuts again before frying. Using a large slotted spoon, transfer a few nuts to the hot oil, allowing the foam to subside before adding another spoonful. (Otherwise, the oil could foam over and burn you.) Fry the nuts until medium brown, about 1 minute for large halves, less time for smaller halves. Be careful not to overcook. lift them out with the spoon and scatter them on a rimmed baking sheet to cool slightly. Fry the remaining nuts in the same way, always working in small batches. While the nuts are still warm, transfer them to a bowl and sprinkle evenly with about half of the spice mix. Toss well to distribute the spices and then taste a nut. Add more spice mix to taste and toss well after each addition. let cool completely, then store in a tightly capped jar. They will keep at room temperature for about 2 weeks. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poppy Seed Dressing</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=81</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dressing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=81</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This goes great with any salad with bitter greens. I think I stole it from http://www.allrecipes.com 1/3 cup white sugar 1/2 cup white vinegar 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon ground dry mustard 1 teaspoon grated onion 1 cup vegetable oil 1 tablespoon poppy seeds Blend together for a while till smooth.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This goes great with any salad with bitter greens. I think I stole it from http://www.allrecipes.com</p>
<p>1/3 cup white sugar<br />
1/2 cup white vinegar<br />
1 teaspoon salt<br />
1 teaspoon ground dry mustard<br />
1 teaspoon grated onion<br />
1 cup vegetable oil<br />
1 tablespoon poppy seeds</p>
<p>Blend together for a while till smooth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nikki&#8217;s Healthy Cookies</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=79</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 20:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snacks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=79</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A friend sent me these, they also work well as bars. Great for hiking or to keep in the office. 3 large, ripe bananas, well mashed (about 1 1/2 cups) 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1/4 cup coconut oil, barely warm &#8211; so it isn&#8217;t solid (or alternately, olive oil) 2 cups rolled oats 2/3 cup &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=79" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Nikki&#8217;s Healthy Cookies</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A friend sent me these, they also work well as bars. Great for hiking or to keep in the office.</p>
<p>3 large, ripe bananas, well mashed (about 1 1/2 cups)<br />
1 teaspoon vanilla extract<br />
1/4 cup coconut oil, barely warm &#8211; so it isn&#8217;t solid (or alternately, olive oil)<br />
2 cups rolled oats<br />
2/3 cup almond meal<br />
1/3 cup coconut, finely shredded &#038; unsweetened<br />
1/2 teaspoon cinnamon<br />
1/2 teaspoon fine grain sea salt<br />
1 teaspoon baking powder<br />
6 &#8211; 7 ounces chocolate chips or dark chocolate bar chopped</p>
<p>Preheat oven to 350 degrees, racks in the top third.</p>
<p>In a large bowl combine the bananas, vanilla extract, and coconut oil. Set aside. In another bowl whisk together the oats, almond meal, shredded coconut, cinnamon, salt, and baking powder. Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and stir until combined. Fold in the chocolate chunks/chips.The dough is a bit looser than a standard cookie dough, don&#8217;t worry about it. Drop dollops of the dough, each about 2 teaspoons in size, an inch apart, onto a parchment (or Silpat) lined baking sheet. Bake for 12 &#8211; 14 minutes. I baked these as long as possible without burning the bottoms and they were perfect &#8211; just shy of 15 minutes seems to be about right in my oven.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Perogies</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=77</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 19:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pasta]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=77</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From: http://pittsburgh.about.com/od/recipes/r/pierogies.htm Ingredients: 2 cups flour, plus extra for kneading and rolling dough 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 large egg 1/2 cup sour cream, plus extra to serve with the pierogi 1/4 cup butter, softened and cut into small pieces butter and onions for sauteing ingredients for filling Pierogi Dough: To prepare the pierogi dough, mix &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=77" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Perogies</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From: http://pittsburgh.about.com/od/recipes/r/pierogies.htm</p>
<p>Ingredients:<br />
2 cups flour, plus extra for kneading and rolling dough<br />
1/2 teaspoon salt<br />
1 large egg<br />
1/2 cup sour cream, plus extra to serve with the pierogi<br />
1/4 cup butter, softened and cut into small pieces<br />
butter and onions for sauteing<br />
ingredients for filling</p>
<p>Pierogi Dough:<br />
To prepare the pierogi dough, mix together the flour and salt. Beat the egg, then add all at once to the flour mixture. Add the 1/2 cup sour cream and the softened butter pieces and work until the dough loses most of its stickiness (about 5-7 minutes). You can use a food processor with a dough hook for this, but be careful not to overbeat. Wrap the dough in plastic and refrigerate for 20-30 minutes or overnight; the dough can be kept in the refrigerator for up to 2 days. Each batch of dough makes about 12-15 pierogies, depending on size.</p>
<p>Roll the pierogi dough on a floured board or countertop until 1/8&#8243; thick. Cut circles of dough (2&#8243; for small pierogies and 3-3 1/2&#8243; for large pierogies) with a cookie cutter or drinking glass. Place a small ball of filling (about a tablespoon) on each dough round and fold the dough over, forming a semi-circle. Press the edges together with the tines of a fork.</p>
<p>Boil the perogies a few at a time in a large pot of water. They are done when they float to the top (about 8-10 minutes). Rinse in cool water and let dry.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crepes</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=72</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 19:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=72</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1 cup all-purpose flour 2 eggs 1/2 cup milk 1/2 cup water 1/4 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons butter, melted]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1 cup all-purpose flour<br />
2 eggs<br />
1/2 cup milk<br />
1/2 cup water<br />
1/4 teaspoon salt<br />
2 tablespoons butter, melted</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mexican Lentil Stew</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=69</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 14:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexican]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soup]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=69</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Got this one from my girlfriend; modified a bit. 2 cups dry lentils 2 Tbsp olive oil 1 medium red onion 1 bell pepper 1 small can corn 4 cloves garlic 2 14.5 oz cans fire roasted diced tomatoes 4 cups veggie broth 1/4 tsp tumeric 1/4 tsp cumin 1/4 tsp sage 1 tsp chili &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=69" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Mexican Lentil Stew</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/20110130-074438.jpg"><img src="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/20110130-074438.jpg" alt="" class="alignnone size-full" /></a></p>
<p>Got this one from my girlfriend; modified a bit.</p>
<p>2 cups dry lentils<br />
2 Tbsp olive oil<br />
1 medium red onion<br />
1 bell pepper<br />
1 small can corn<br />
4 cloves garlic<br />
2 14.5 oz cans fire roasted diced tomatoes<br />
4 cups veggie broth<br />
1/4 tsp tumeric<br />
1/4 tsp cumin<br />
1/4 tsp sage<br />
1 tsp chili powder<br />
1 lime<br />
1/2 tsp sage<br />
1 handful cilantro<br />
1 tsp habinero relish for heat</p>
<p>STEP 1: In a medium pot, bring the 2 cups of lentils and 4 cups of water to a boil. Once it reaches a boil, turn off the heat and let sit with a lid on for about 20 minutes.<br />
STEP 2: Cook onions in oil for a few minutes. Add garlic and cook for 30 seconds to release flavor. Add bell pepper and cook a bit<br />
STEP 3: Cook the onions etc until they are soft but not brown. Add the cans of diced tomatoes, vegetable broth, spices, and corn. Continue to cook over medium heat until hot.<br />
STEP 4: At this point, the lentils should have absorbed the water and become soft. Add the lentils and any remaining water to the soup mixture. Stir well and slightly mash using the back of your spoon.<br />
STEP 5: Once the entire mixture is hot, add a handful of chopped cilantro and taste test to<br />
see if you want any more heat, salt or pepper.<br />
STEP 6: Squeeze juice of 1/2 lime in and serve. I serve with greek yogart.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iphone Restore from Recovery Mode</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=61</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 15:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=61</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I woke up with my iphone telling me to plug it into itunes. I did, and it started to update and restore the software, which failed. Afterwards, the phone still didn&#8217;t boot past the &#8220;plug into itunes&#8221; screen, but itunes wouldn&#8217;t recognize it to try to restore again. After a lot of digging, I found &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=61" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Iphone Restore from Recovery Mode</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I woke up with my iphone telling me to plug it into itunes. I did, and it started to update and restore the software, which failed.</p>
<p>Afterwards, the phone still didn&#8217;t boot past the &#8220;plug into itunes&#8221; screen, but itunes wouldn&#8217;t recognize it to try to restore again.</p>
<p>After a lot of digging, I found how to force the phone into &#8220;Recovery Mode&#8221; again: as you turn it on, hold the top and home buttons. After the connect to itunes screen appears, release the top button but keep holding the home button. This will make re-register itself as an apple recovery mode device.</p>
<p>After that, the restore still failed, so I shift-clicked restore and selected a fresh .ipsw I downloaded online. That also failed with error code 1015. I did it one more time from apple, and it worked, but then it consistently booted into recovery mode.</p>
<p>This guide: http://www.ihackintosh.com/2009/07/irecovery-iphone-recovery-mode-loop-restart/ sorted that out. Nice usb utility too.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quick Tomato Sauce</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=60</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 04:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pasta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sauce]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=60</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This was from America&#8217;s Test Kitchen. It&#8217;s super fast and easy to add other goodies. 1 28 oz can crushed tomatoes 1/4 cup grated onion 2 tbls butter 1/4 tsp oregano 1/2 teaspoon salt 2 cloves garlic 1/4 teaspoon sugar 1 tbl olive oil 2 tbls minced garlic Salt/pepper to taste Melt butter in a &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=60" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Quick Tomato Sauce</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This was from America&#8217;s Test Kitchen. It&#8217;s super fast and easy to add other goodies.</p>
<p>1 28 oz can crushed tomatoes<br />
1/4 cup grated onion<br />
2 tbls butter<br />
1/4 tsp oregano<br />
1/2 teaspoon salt<br />
2 cloves garlic<br />
1/4 teaspoon sugar<br />
1 tbl olive oil<br />
2 tbls minced garlic<br />
Salt/pepper to taste</p>
<p>Melt butter in a saucepan, grated onion and oregona and cook till onions turn brown. Add 1/2 teaspoon table salt and press garlic into pot. Cook 30 seconds to release flavor.<br />
Add crushed tomatoes and sugar. Turn to high heat and bring to quick simmer.<br />
Turn to med-low and cook for 10 minutes to thicken.<br />
Take off heat and add olive oil and basil. Salt/pepper to taste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mom&#8217;s Meatloaf Sauce</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=59</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 04:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=59</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I always forget this 1/4 cup ketchup 2 tbls brown sugar 1 tsp dry mustard]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I always forget this</p>
<p>1/4 cup ketchup<br />
2 tbls brown sugar<br />
1 tsp dry mustard</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Mom&#8217;s Pumpkin Bread</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=58</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 04:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My mom&#8217;s recipe. You can swap the oil for 1c apple sauce + 1/4 cup oil. 3 1/2 cups flour (I use 2 1/4 c whole wheat, 1 1/4 c white) 2 tsp baking soda 1 1/2 tsp salt 1 tsp nutmeg 1 tbls cinnamon 1 cup oil 4 eggs, lightly beaten 2/3 &#8211; 1 &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=58" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">My Mom&#8217;s Pumpkin Bread</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My mom&#8217;s recipe. You can swap the oil for 1c apple sauce + 1/4 cup oil.</p>
<p>3 1/2 cups flour (I use 2 1/4 c whole wheat, 1 1/4 c white)<br />
2 tsp baking soda<br />
1 1/2 tsp salt<br />
1 tsp nutmeg<br />
1 tbls cinnamon<br />
1 cup oil<br />
4 eggs, lightly beaten<br />
2/3 &#8211; 1 cup water<br />
2 cups (1 15-16 oz can) pumpkin<br />
3 cups sugar</p>
<p>Mix dry ingredients, add oil, eggs, water and mix well.  Add pumpkin and<br />
stir; add sugar and stir.  Bake 1 1/2 hours at 325°F for two large loaves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pancakes</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=53</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 03:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakfast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=53</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the pancake recipe I use. It&#8217;s good. I found it somewhere online, but changed it a bit to my taste. Ingredients: 1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour 4 1/2 teaspoons baking powder 1 teaspoon salt 1 tablespoon white sugar 1 1/4 cups milk 1 egg 3 tablespoons butter, melted Whisk together and make pancakes. &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=53" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Pancakes</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the pancake recipe I use. It&#8217;s good. I found it somewhere online, but changed it a bit to my taste.</p>
<p>Ingredients:<br />
1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour<br />
4 1/2 teaspoons baking powder<br />
1 teaspoon salt<br />
1 tablespoon white sugar<br />
1 1/4 cups milk<br />
1 egg<br />
3 tablespoons butter, melted</p>
<p>Whisk together and make pancakes.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve occassionally made half the flour whole wheat, and it&#8217;s good too, but a bit tougher.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I moved to wordpress</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=54</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 03:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=54</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is for 2 reasons: 1) I can easily make posts with pictures from my phone 2) Its easier to look at posts from my phone Since I want to use this mostly for recipes, this makes sense.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is for 2 reasons:<br />
1) I can easily make posts with pictures from my phone<br />
2) Its easier to look at posts from my phone</p>
<p>Since I want to use this mostly for recipes, this makes sense.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I made this for a housewarming yesterday&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=4</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 18:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I made this for a housewarming yesterday, came out really tastey. Was excellent for breakfast this morning too. read more]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made this for a housewarming yesterday, came out really tastey.  Was excellent for breakfast this morning too.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/17">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pidgin spellcheck problem in Kubuntu 9.04</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=5</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 21:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I ran into a weird spellcheck problem with pidgin in kubuntu 9.04. Pidgin uses the gtkspell library, but it kept telling me every word was spelled wrong. If I ran it with LANG=en_US pidgin Everything worked fine. I didn&#039;t find much on the net, but installing aspell seems to have fixed the problem&#8230; somewhere o.O.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I ran into a weird spellcheck problem with pidgin in kubuntu 9.04.  Pidgin uses the gtkspell library, but it kept telling me every word was spelled wrong.  If I ran it with<br />
<code>LANG=en_US pidgin<br />
</code><br />
Everything worked fine. I didn&#039;t find much on the net, but installing aspell seems to have fixed the problem&#8230; somewhere o.O.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Widescreen DVD creation in Linux</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=6</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 04:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linux]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I recently wanted to make some widescreen dvds to pass on to my parents. I remember trying this before, but having nothing but headaches. Fortunately, software updates have made dvd authoring pretty easy. Here is how I did it in linux using only command line utilities. I wanted to make a disk that just had &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=6" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Widescreen DVD creation in Linux</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I recently wanted to make some widescreen dvds to pass on to my parents.  I remember trying this before, but having nothing but headaches.  Fortunately, software updates have made dvd authoring pretty easy.  Here is how I did it in linux using only command line utilities.</p>
<p>I wanted to make a disk that just had the movie (no menu&#039;s, etc), and have it play in a regular ntsc dvd player.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/15">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bridge Walk!</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=7</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 22:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The nice weather recently allowed me to try out the gps on my iphone. I tracked a nice walk I took across the Ben Franklin. I accidentally stopped the tracking before I got home, but most of it tracked pretty well. Map below. read more]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The nice weather recently allowed me to try out the gps on my iphone.  I tracked a nice walk I took across the Ben Franklin.  I accidentally stopped the tracking before I got home, but most of it tracked pretty well.  Map below.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/14">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>pdflatex and errors with IEEE PDF eXpress</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=8</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 20:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#039;ve been preparing a paper for publication in CVPR, and ran into some problems getting my pdf to pass the IEEE checks. Specifically, in PDF eXpress I got the following errors: Document contains Link annotation(s) (98x on pages 1-8) Font Helvetica is not embedded The fixes on the IEEE website aren&#039;t very helpful if you &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=8" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">pdflatex and errors with IEEE PDF eXpress</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#039;ve been preparing a paper for publication in CVPR, and ran into some problems getting my pdf to pass the IEEE checks.  Specifically, in PDF eXpress I got the following errors:<br />
<code>Document contains Link annotation(s) (98x on pages 1-8)<br />
Font Helvetica is not embedded<br />
</code><br />
The fixes on the IEEE website aren&#039;t very helpful if you are using pdflatex (they all reference editing the pdf in acrobat pro).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/13">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MPI Error Fix</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=9</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2009 04:08:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nerd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#039;ve been doing a lot of MPI development recently, and had a few MPI programs that crashed. After this happened, I kept receiving the following error on when using mpi-lam: The selected RPI failed to initialize during MPI_INIT. read more]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#039;ve been doing a lot of MPI development recently, and had a few MPI programs that crashed.  After this happened, I kept receiving the following error on when using mpi-lam:</p>
<p>The selected RPI failed to initialize during MPI_INIT.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/12">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strawberry Pie With Jennie visiting and &#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=10</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 01:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Strawberry Pie With Jennie visiting and the last of the pear pie meeting its timely death upon the season 1 finale of &#8220;Bones&#8221;, I decided to try making a strawberry pie. I wanted to be a little more experimental this time, so the recipe below is more like a best guess as to what went &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=10" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Strawberry Pie With Jennie visiting and &#8230;</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="float: right; padding-right: 10px;"><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/files/IMG_4209.jpg"><img src="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/files/IMG_4209_thumb.jpg" border=0></a><br />
<center><font size="1"> <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/files/IMG_4209.jpg">Strawberry Pie</a></font></div>
<p>With Jennie visiting and the last of the pear pie meeting its timely death upon the season 1 finale of &#8220;Bones&#8221;, I decided to try making a strawberry pie.  I wanted to be a little more experimental this time, so the recipe below is more like a best guess as to what went into mine.  One thing is for certain: buy a lot of strawberries! I don&#039;t think you can have too much, and I was debating how to put more on before I went to bed. I did a lot of research for this one, and specifically wanted to avoid any &#8220;cheating&#8221;, specifically with regards to using strawberry jello, food coloring, or kool aid.  I settled on a vartiation of <a href="http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Strawberry-Pie-II/Detail.aspx">this</a> recipe.  I also tried a different crust recipe that makes more of a pastry.  I based it off a recipe from <a href="http://whatscookingamerica.net/piecrst.htm">here</a>, but changed a bit since the provided recipe just seemed to much like a pastry.  I&#039;ll put the crust at the bottom as you could just use whatever or buy store-bought.  I also made lemon whipped cream to top it off, which turned out amazing!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/8">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gold Diggers of 1933</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=11</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 09:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Picture from wikipedia Tonight Missy and I went to the Lawn Chair Drive In and saw Gold Diggers of 1933. Contrary to the title, the movie isn&#039;t really about Gold Diggers, but is a musical about show girls during the depression. Overall pretty entertaining, and much better to watch outside on 16mm if you have &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=11" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Gold Diggers of 1933</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="float: left; padding-right: 10px;"><img src="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/files/2008_07_15_GoldDiggerThumb.jpg"><br />
<center><font size="1">Picture from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:Gold_Diggers_1933_poster.jpg">wikipedia</a></font></div>
<p>Tonight Missy and I went to the <a href="http://lawnchairdrivein.com/Site/Home.html">Lawn Chair Drive In</a> and saw <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0024069/">Gold Diggers of 1933</a>.  Contrary to the title, the movie isn&#039;t really about Gold Diggers, but is a musical about show girls during the depression.  Overall pretty entertaining, and much better to watch outside on 16mm if you have the op.  Also, there were some pretty amusing situations that fans of As You Like It and Sabrina may find familiar.  I would dig finding some of those swinging tunes from the picture, but I imagine that would be a feat.  Most of the music was dancey-showy music or classic romance, as expected from old films.  One thing that threw me for a loop was the last song, which suddenly became a huge world war 1 statement directly proceeding the credits.  It seemed really out of place compared to the rest of the movie (first act: comedy, second act: romance), and didn&#039;t bode well with the previous &#8220;numbers&#8221;.  Overall the movie was meant to be an uplift for people dealing with the depression, and hopefully relate to the situation and drive some sales to the box office (they hung this lantern pretty high aka- producer&#039;s style), so I figure the last song must have been along those lines.</p>
<p>Probably more entertaining than the actual movie was a short that aired before it about the jitterbug, posted below.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/7">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>This weekend I was visiting Kristin and &#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=12</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 01:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[louis]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This weekend I was visiting Kristin and she mentioned to me her recent successes with pie making. Being extremely susceptible to the power of suggestion (and pie), I decided to try my wits about it. Kristin was kind enough to lend me her recipe for crust, and suggest some simple pie approaches on allrecipes.com. I &#8230; <a href="http://www.riothamus.net/wp/?p=12" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">This weekend I was visiting Kristin and &#8230;</span> <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I was visiting <a href="http://kribit.com">Kristin</a> and she mentioned to me her recent successes with pie making.  Being extremely susceptible to the power of suggestion (and pie), I decided to try my wits about it.  Kristin was kind enough to lend me her recipe for crust, and suggest some simple pie approaches on <a href="http://allrecipes.com">allrecipes.com</a>.  I opted for the <a href="http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Fresh-Pear-Pie/Detail.aspx">Fresh Pear Pie</a>, as it was rather simple and I only needed to buy two ingredients.  After a quick trip to the market I was off messing up my kitchen that Sean and I spent so much time cleaning this weekend.  I&#039;m not sure how it tastes yet, as I am waiting for some friends to come over and try it, but here is the recipe! I didn&#039;t change anything as I figured my first pie shouldn&#039;t be experimental. In addition, I forgot the butter in the pie, hope it turns out okay.  I had a terrible time rolling out the dough, but figure its a practice thing!  I&#039;ll change the picture if I ever get a digital camera.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.riothamus.net/drupal/?q=node/6">read more</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
